<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Vahan Aslanyan</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Vahan Aslanyan</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 12 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Recent Talks and Presentations</title>
      <link>/talk/talks/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/talk/talks/</guid>
      <description>1. Direct versus stratified covariate adjustment in continuous outcome adaptive randomization for randomized controlled trials. Event: Joint Statistical Meetings Date: August 7, 2024 Location: Portland Convention Center Description: This talk focused on the extension of my first dissertation project. I compared direct and stratified adjustment for allocation and covariate imbalances in simulated scenarios. 2. Protective effects of sleep duration and physical activity on cognitive performance are influenced by amyloid beta and brain volume but not tau burden among cognitively unimpaired older adults.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cerebrovascular Reactivity and Mild Cognitive Impairment</title>
      <link>/2023/12/18/cerebrovascular-reactivity-and-mild-cognitive-impairment/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2023/12/18/cerebrovascular-reactivity-and-mild-cognitive-impairment/</guid>
      <description>Very happy that my recent work has been published in Alzheimer&amp;rsquo;s &amp;amp; Dementia. In this project, we have used data from Systolic Blood Pressure Intervention Trial Memory and Cognition in Decreased Hypertension (SPRINT-MIND) magnetic resonance imaging sub-study to evaluate the association of cerebrovascular reactivity, a measure of brain blood vessel elasticity, with mild cognitive impairment and dementia. We found that cerebrovascular reactivity in AD signature regions is negatively associated with occurrence of mild cognitive impairment, implicating cerebrovascular reactivity in these signature regions as a potential mechanism leading to cognitive impairment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About me</title>
      <link>/page/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/page/about/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m a Biostatistics PhD student at University of Southern California. I am interested in adaptive designs for randomized controlled trials in Alzheimer&amp;rsquo;s Disease. My dissertation focuses on:
Bayesian covariate-adjusted response adaptive randomization for continuous outcomes Sample size considerations for response adaptive randomized trials Interim decisions for response adaptive randomize trials with sample size re-estimation properties Before starting my PhD, I worked with neuroimaging data at USC INI. I have graduated from UC Berkeley with BA in Statistics and Applied Mathematics.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
